I was a student in the '60s, a time of social upheaval and questioning,
كنت طالباً في الستينيات، وقت الإضطرابات الإجتماعية والمسائلة
and -- on a personal level -- an awakening sense of idealism.
وعلى المستوى الشخصي، في صحوة الشعور بالمثالية
The war in Vietnam was raging, the Civil Rights movement was under way
الحرب في فيتنام كانت مستعرة ؛ حركة الحقوق المدنية جارية
and pictures had a powerful influence on me.
وكان للصوّر تأثير قوي عليّ
Our political and military leaders were telling us one thing
كان قادتنا السياسيين والعسكريين يخبروننا بشئ واحد
and photographers were telling us another.
والمصوّرين يخبروننا بشئ مختلف
I believed the photographers and so did millions of other Americans.
لقد صدقت المصوّرين وكذلك فعل الملايين من بقية الأمريكيين
Their images fuelled resistance to the war and to racism.
صورهم أوقدت المقاومة للحرب والعنصرية
They not only recorded history -- they helped change the course of history.
لم يسجلوا فقط التاريخ، لقد ساعدوا في تغيير مسار التاريخ
Their pictures became part of our collective consciousness
صورهم أصبحت جزء من وعينا الجماعي
and, as consciousness evolved into a shared sense of conscience,
وكما يتطور الوعي الى إحساس مشترك بالوعي
change became not only possible, but inevitable.
لم يصبح التغيير فقط ممكناً، بل حتميا
It puts a human face on issues which, from afar,
إنه يضع وجه إنساني على القضايا البعيدة
can appear abstract or ideological or monumental in their global impact.
قد تبدو نظرية أو إيدلوجية أو هائلة في تأثيرها العالمي
What happens at ground level, far from the halls of power,
ما يحدث على أرض الواقع، بعيدا عن أروقة السلطة
happens to ordinary citizens one by one.
يحدث لمواطنين عاديين واحد تلو الآخر
And I understood that documentary photography
وفهمت أن التصوير الوثائقي
has the ability to interpret events from their point of view.
لديه القدرة على ترجمة الأحداث من وجهة نظرها
It gives a voice to those who otherwise would not have a voice.
إنه يعطي الصوت للذين بدونه لن يكون لديهم صوت
My TED wish. There’s a vital story that needs to be told
أمنية تيد خاصتي. هناك قصة حيوية يجب أن تروى
and I wish for TED to help me gain access to it
وأتمنى أن يساعدني تيد في أن أصل اليها
and then to help me come up with innovative and exciting ways
وحينها أن يساعدني في الوصول لطرق مبتكرة ومثيرة
to use news photography in the digital era.
لإستخدام التصوير الفوتوغرافي في العصر الرقمي
Thank you very much.
شكراً جزيلاً لكم
[ 10.3.08 -- The story breaks. ]
[10.3.08 --بدأت القصة]
[ "I have been a witness, and these pictures are my testimony." ]
["وقد كنت شاهداً، وهذه الصوّر هي شهادتي" ]
[ South Africa ]
[جنوب افريقيا]
[ This is happening now. ]
[ This is happening now. ]
[ Cambodia ]
[كمبوديا]
[ Swaziland ]
[سوازيلاند]
[ One person dies every 20 seconds. ]
[شخص واحد يموت كل 20 ثانية. ]
[ Thailand ]
[تايلاند]
[ An ancient disease is taking on a deadly new form. ]
[مرض قديم مميت يأخذ شكلاً جديداً. ]
[ Siberia ]
[سيبريا ]
[ Lesotho ]
[لسوسو]
[ Tuberculosis: the next pandemic? ]
[السل : الوباء القادم؟ ]
[ India ]
[الهند]
[ TB is preventable and curable, ]
[السل يمكن الوقاية منه وعلاجه ]
[ but it is mutating due to inadequate treatment. ]
[لكنه يتحور بسبب نقص العلاج. ]
[ XDR-TB: ]
[السُل من نوع XDR: ]
[ extreme drug resistant tuberculosis. ]
[السل الشديد المقاومة للأدوية. ]
[ There is no reliable cure. ]
[لا يوجد دواء موثوق. ]
[ Patients often die within weeks of diagnosis. ]
[يموت المرضى عادة خلال أسابيع من التشخيص. ]
[ 49 countries have reported XDR-TB. ]
[أبلغت 49 دولة عن السُل XDR. ]
[ XDR-TB is a critical threat to global health. ]
[السُل XDR مهدد حرج للصحة العالمية. ]
[ Extreme outbreak, suffering, affliction ]
[إنتشار سريع ]
[ Extreme loss, pain, pandemic ]
[معاناة صعبة ]
[ Extremely preventable. ]
[يمكن الوقاية منه بشدة. ]
[ XDR-TB. ]
[السُل نوع XDR. ]
[ We can stop this now. ]
[يمكننا إيقاف ذلك الآن. ]
[ Spread the story. Stop the disease. ]
[أنشر القصة. أوقف المرض. ]
[ Go to XDRTB.org now. ]
[أذهب الى XDRTB.org الآن. ]
[ XDRTB.org: we are the treatment. ]
[XDRTB.org: نحن العلاج. ]
[ We are the treatment. ]
[نحن العلاج. ]
[ Made possible through the kind support of BD. ]
[ تم التمكين له من خلال الدعم المادي السخي لـ BD. ]